Lee Alan Burton

Personal Details

Nationality: British Place of Birth: U.K.

Email Address: leeburton@shu.edu.cn Twitter Handle: @leeaburton

Office Telephone: +86 021 6613 6129 Website: www.bmd-lab.org

Office Address: E111, Baoshan Campus, Shanghai University, Shanghai, 200444, China

Google Scholar Page: https://scholar.google.com/citations?user=fEp-jzkAAAAJ&hl=en

Linkedin Profile: http://uk.linkedin.com/in/lee-a-burton/

Professional Summary

Status: Associate Professor (full time)

Affiliations: Member of the Royal Society of Chemistry

Accolades: - Chinese National Science Foundation International Young Scientist Award 2019.

- Shanghai Municipal Government Eastern Young Scholar Award 2018.

- European Commission Seal of Excellence 2017.

- Japanese Material Research Society Award for Encouragement of Materials

Research Science 2012.

Publications: 18 peer-review research articles; 3 international patents covering 13 inventions

Metrics: More than 1,000 citations, h-index: 15, 3 first-author papers with >100 citations **Funding Awards:** Early career fellowship, 2 International Research Fellowships, PhD Scholarship

Languages: English (native), French (conversational), mandarin (basic)

Qualifications

Doctoral Qualification: PhD in Sustainable Chemical Technologies, University of Bath, UK.

Undergraduate Degree: Master of Chemistry (Hons), University of Warwick, UK.Other Qualifications: Master of Research (Merit), University of Bath, UK.

Diplôme d'Études en Langue Française (B1), Université Catholique de Louvain

Key Skills Summary

- Project and data management, task delegation, problem solving and international collaboration.
- Programming proficiency in Python 2/3, Bash and LaTeX languages.
- Project proposal, bid evaluation, persuasive and technical writing skills.
- Control of Substances Hazardous to Health (COSHH) and risk assessment practices.
- Numerical and technical analysis, software and computer literacy, 3D visualisation software.
- Budget management, resource allocation and account keeping.
- Multi-disciplinary teamwork, event organisation and laboratory management roles
- Presentation and teaching expertise, data formatting and demographic awareness.
- Public speaking, lecturing, online recording and debating experience.

Employment History

Feb. 2019 to Present – Associate Professor, Shanghai University, China.

- Recipient of Shanghai Oriental Young Scholar early career fellowship.
- Recipient of the Chinese National Science Foundation International Young Scientist Award 2019.
- Tenured faculty position in the Department of Physics.
- Tutorial leader at the 2019 Jiangsu mathematics & computing in materials design graduate summer school
- Lecturer of physics department and guest lecture in international development
- Invited speaker at Asian Materials Data Symposium, 2019

Dec. 2016 to Feb. 2019 – Research Fellow, Université Catholique de Louvain, Belgium.

- Recipient of "Move-In Louvain" research fellowship funded by the EU Marie-Curie actions.
- Recipient of the European Commission Seal of Excellence award 2018.
- Invited speaker & session chair at European Materials Research Society (E-MRS) Meetings 2017 & 2018.
- B1 level Diplôme d'Études en Langue Française (DELF) qualification obtained.
- Invited Speaker, "Out-Thinkers" event, British Science Festival, UK.

Lee Alan Burton

- 2 international patents pending, contribution purchased by Panasonic Corporation.
- Tutorial leader on database querying & high-throughput screening at Materials Research Society (MRS)
 Spring Meeting, USA, 2018

Nov. 2014 to Nov. 2016 -Research Fellow, Tokyo Institute of Technology, Japan.

- Royal Society nominated candidate for maximally funded fellowship with Japanese Society for the Promotion of Science (JSPS)
- Equal shareholder on international patent for 11 novel semiconductors (number WO/2017/065294).
- Speaker at four international conferences and invited contribution to international workshop.
- 5 research articles published in high impact, peer reviewed journals including Nature Communications and Physical Review Letters.
- Japanese language classes and culture engagement activities attended throughout the fellowship.
- Volunteer participant of JSPS Science Dialogue program: lecturing at senior high schools (ages 15-17).

Oct. 2010 to Oct. 2014 - Doctoral Student, University of Bath, UK.

- Multi-disciplinary PhD funded by Engineering and Physical Sciences Research Council scholarship.
 - Recipient of Award for Encouragement of Materials Research Science by Japanese Materials Research Society.
 - o Over 2,000 GBP in external grant money and bursary awards.
- Laboratory custodian of Solar Instrument Room, Department of Chemistry.
 - o Developed control and safety standards for contemporary lab space.
 - Implemented training and operating protocols for hazardous experimental procedures.
- Public engagement and ambassadorial roles for the Centre for Sustainable Chemical Technologies.
 - o Elected Ambassador to the UK Energy Research Network for the Bath graduate school.
 - o Invited speaker for the British Science Association's 'Science Café' public presentation.
 - o University of Bath STEM (Science, Technology, Engineering and Mathematics) ambassador.
- Casual Demonstrator and teaching assistant.

Dec. 2013 to May 2014 - Events Manager, "Pint of Science" festival, Bath, UK.

• Theme leader of 'Planet Earth' section, Bath chapter, for international science festival 'Pint of Science'.

Nov. 2013 to Apr. 2014 – Conference Organiser, Royal Society of Chemistry, UK.

- Organising committee member for the RSC, Solid State Group Easter Meeting, Buckinghamshire, UK.
- Responsibilities included: budget allocations, costing, talk selection and program design.

Jul. 2013 to Dec. 2013 – Visiting Scholar, Harvard University, USA.

- Established international collaboration between the University of Bath (UK), Harvard University (USA) and the Massachusetts Institute of Technology (USA).
- Involved multiple visits between UK & USA, confidential data handling and regular teleconferencing.

Oct. 2010 to Sep. 2011 – Master of Research, University of Bath, UK.

Degree with taught courses and 2 research projects: battery cathodes and materials for hydrogen storage

Apr. 2009 to Sep. 2009 – Research Intern, University of Tasmania, Australia.

• Designed and built a 2-D gas chromatography suite to analyse oil spills for Australian Antarctic Division.

References on Request **Professor Aron Walsh**, **Professor Fumiyasu Oba Professor David Scanlon** Royal School of Mines. Laboratory for Materials & Structures, Department of Chemistry, Imperial College London, Tokyo Institute of Technology, University College London, London, WC1H 0AJ London, SW7 2BP Yokohama 226-8503 United Kingdom United Kingdom Japan oba@msl.titech.ac.jp a.walsh@imperial.ac.uk d.scanlon@ucl.ac.uk +44 (0)20 7594 1178 +81 (0)45-924-5511 +44 (0)20 7679 4558